The majority of online businesses work.
I'm not here to say that they don't.
Instead,
I'm giving my time to help improve the
processes.
Imagine if I was your personal trainer,
which I used to do for quite a few years.
By making some changes to your program,
your split, your supplementation
regime,
we could take the same amount of effort
and get better results from it.
I do the same now in business.
If you want to send me your socials so I
can do this
for you,
there's a link in the description below.
I'm going to start today with a very
interesting one.
This is Justin Price,
and I've not looked
or researched any of this before starting
this video. Straight away,
we land on the profile,
"I help athletes increase speed
and power." This is brilliant.
So many people try
and overcomplicate their mission
statement. Love to see it.
"Owner of." Some people
are very quick to call
themselves founders. It's like,
what did you found, mate?
A website and some programs. No offense.
This could easily have just said,
"I run Speed Academy," or,
"Check out Speed
Academy." And here,
"Programs to sprint faster." As far as
bio, this is very good.
One thing that I'm kind of frothing at the
moment is what I would call dark mode.
So if we go to YouTube here,
you'll notice I think over 60% of people
now use
dark mode on YouTube,
which means they prefer having a darker
backdrop when they're
on webpages. Same with Discord.
When I'm on Discord, I like the text
being a bit lighter
and the background being a bit darker.
So the second I land on here,
I would love to see a dark mode.
And if using a platform like Leadpages,
we'd be able to A/B split test that.
You could have dark mode, light mode.
You could split your traffic 50/50,
and we could then see whether or not the
conversion rate on that was an uptake
or downtake or whatever. I could be wrong.
I'm just saying this from an inclination.
I'd love for you to turn around and go,
"Bro, shut the fuck up.
My page with a lighter backdrop performs
better." Let's have a look at your VSL.
The Speed Academy is a 12-month online
training program for athletes looking to
significantly-
Love the fact that you've just gone
straight into it. You're introducing it.
"I'm Justin.
I went to college in Arkansas." "My name's
Justin.
I went to university in Kansas City,
and I have a
bachelor..." None of that. You're just in.
... increase their speed even
if you have terrible genetics
or limited time to
train. Your time-
The terrible genetics thing,
that's genius because the majority of fast
runners
have got incredible genetics,
and people that would buy your program
are actually
those with inferior genetics looking to
get ahead.
I'm really enjoying this, Justin.
By 0.2 to 1.0 seconds in one to six months
without having
to train-
Some specificity there as well. Love it
... over 45 minutes a day. Plus,
if you don't increase your speed in the
first 30
days,
you have a 30-day money-back guarantee,
so you have-
Exceptional.
Absolutely bloody exceptional.
Again, the biggest hesitation I have
when I'm on this page is what
if I don't get
faster?
Nothing to lose in this limited time
offer.
This program builds speed, lower body
and upper body strength, vertical jump,
and raw explosiveness. The goal
is to see consistent gains every single
month with
our pro-level speed training year-round.
This program has helped athletes go from
4.7 to 4.3 in the 40 yard and
4.8 to 4.4 FAT in the 40 yard.
I've also trained Division 1
soccer, track and field,
and basketball players.
This program-
This could be one of the best VSLs I've
ever seen
...
is designed for intermediate to advanced
athletes with a couple years of
training under their belt who
are looking to get faster consistently.
But this program also has exercise
regressions for beginner athletes
and separate
training plans for athletes who
are in season with their sport.
If you're in a sport
that requires speed
and quickness like soccer, football,
basketball, or track and field,
then this speed training program
is perfect for
you.
So if you're ready to transform your
running speed, drop your 40-yard time,
and even-
Incredible. "Sign up now, $27 monthly,
cancel any time." Okay,
there's a few more videos now.
One thing that I do-
Before the Speed Academy program,
I ran a 4.9-
Sometimes I feel like too many videos can
be overkill. I think that's enough.
I think anything more than
that could potentially be overkill.
Look inside the program. See, look,
there's just a few too many videos for my
liking. I like this visual representation.
This is really good.
I think from here we could probably just
have, again, probably too many videos
here, mate. Too much of the repetition.
Another video.
Some of these would be great,
just some very short bits of feedback.
That would've been fine. Again, what
are we at now? 10 videos?
I just don't think that's necessary.
Your VSL is so good.
Everything here is just a little bit of
overkill.
I think this could be much more succinct.
So we've got this.
Give me some swipe-through testimonials,
a little look into the app. Buy now.
Boom. Really impressive.
Is this called TSA? Is
that like your airport thing?
Okay, let's have a look at your Instagram.
If you have weak hips and no speed,
try these four drills to get your hip
flexors
more active.
One issue here would be the music can be
too loud.
So many people, again,
I can't say this enough, if your music
is too loud, you just
ruin the video because now I can't hear
what you're saying.
Was the song that important? Probably not.
If someone can't hear you,
they're just going to leave.
Weak and unathletic? These
are the fundamentals.
Number one is sprint two times per week.
Breaking down Usain Bolt's speed workout.
The first one's for hip mobility work.
He does the hurdles,
or really just with the imagination.
Breaking down elite-level college speed
training.
First is-
So I think the hooks could do with a
little bit of work.
So for instance, this one
Breaking down elite-level college speed
training.
First-
I think a hook there could be,
"Have you ever wondered why elite athletes
do this
weird type of running? Well,
this type of running is called,
and this is how it
helps."
One of the biggest reasons why you're so
slow is because you simply cannot
stabilize in multiple directions at the
ankle.
If you can't do drills-
"Did you know most people looking to get
faster neglect ankle strength and
stability, and that's why they stay slow?
In this video,
I'm going to show you some ankle
strengthening techniques."
Athletes,
here's the absolute fundamentals to
getting faster.
Number one-
"If you're someone that wishes they
were faster, here
are some things you can try."
I'm coming for it all.
If you want to improve your acceleration
like these athletes right here, then-
Great hook
Athletes, these drills will help-
So the one thing here is,
as you look through,
you can definitely see which one of
these end up being outliers. Ooh.
And this athlete is just your average guy.
What makes him so much faster than the
average guy?
I'm going to give you the three reasons
why so you can become a faster athlete.
Let's reuse that hook again. This
is really, really, really, really good.
Now, the only thing is all of these,
no call to actions.
If you were to get ManyChat,
I'll give you a brief,
quick insight to those of you
maybe using it. You can pick an account.
I've got one here. Go to Automation.
New automation. Start from scratch.
New trigger.
So you're probably going to want someone
to comment on your post.
Let's do next post or reel,
so then you know whatever you're putting
out next.
Comments to include, "Faster." Cool.
And then maybe we might even do it just in
case they had a spelling mistake.
I don't know. Cool.
So we could then say on the post, "Hey,
guys, if you comment
the word faster,
the world of running faster is only a
few weeks away. Click the link below,
and I'll send
45 ways in 45 days to get
faster for free.
Thanks for watching my content.
Justin." Then here we could go,
"Get fast." Maybe even like on a
lightning bolt, "Get fast on
www.fasterthanlasttime.com."
I'm just making that up. You get it. Cool.
So now suddenly, you're incentivized
that every time you have a post like
that one
that absolutely blows up,
you're going to be getting people firing
into your email
list.
Because that's the only thing I don't see
here.
It looks like we're going traffic,
landing page, landing page, conversions.
Cool. Great.
But I would love to see between socials
and between landing page
opportunities to get someone's email
address.
So I think a chatbot automation for
that would crush.
And I suppose,
let me tell you why I'm saying all of
this.
Don't tell them, show them, James.
Don't tell them, show them.
Because over the years,
all of my social media strategy has been
about taking
people from social media
and getting their email address.
That means that as my brand
and as your brands over time morph
and change,
we can do certain things. So for instance,
this is just one of my email marketing
platforms. I much prefer Klaviyo
and I much prefer AWeber, but
hear me out.
So over here where we've got the
recipients, I've got some different
lists here. You'll notice
that my daily emails list has got
403,000 people. 403,000 people. So
when we launched Nutonic, it
was very handy that we had
400,000 email addresses. Now,
some of these segmentations, so this is
just what I use for my fitness app. So
if social media goes down tomorrow, I'm
cool. I've got 400,000 email addresses.
Now, we've
cleaned this recently,
7,000 people with an account.
We've got some people on this plan,
this plan.
But then if you look at some of my
segments here, we've got super engaged.
That means they've opened an email within,
I don't know, the last 24 hours.
We've got past customers
that we can message,
and then we've got people that have
trialed and never purchased.
And the reason for email list segmentation
is, one,
if someone's trialed the platform
but they've not used a paid program,
I can send
them a certain campaign.
If someone's been a customer before,
it's more of a
re-engagement campaign.
Joined via micro calculator,
162,000 just from a macronutrient
calculator.
Having the ability to push a message to
hundreds of thousands of people at the
same
time is such an integral part of running a
business, so that in the future, people
will have used me for my fitness app.
And I'll put a link to
that in the description if any of you,
you can do all your
workouts from 10 pound a month.
I'll also put a link in there for Nutonic
where,
put it this way,
I'm going to turn up on this channel
indefinitely and give out
advice for free.
I don't even monetize this channel because
it's that focused on
giving you as much value as I can.
If you try this product
and you don't love it,
you message me and I'll refund you out my
own money.
So Justin,
you know the first thing I'm going to ask
you is how many people are on
your email list? And if that answer
is zero, we have a problem.
I was doing a live call last night with
Mike Thurston for some of his mastermind
people. He told me that his email list
was petite.
I said, "Bro, how can you have arms
that big, Mike Thurston,
and yet have such a
petite email list?
It doesn't make sense." Let's go over to
your
YouTube.
"I help the average athlete sprint
faster." You see this TSA thing?
Not only is it making me feel like I need
to take my shoes off at the airport, it
just doesn't do anything.
It just doesn't do anything.
Just get rid of it.
"I help the average athlete sprint
faster." I love that. Cool.
"I've trained 10.2,
4.5." Doesn't do anything. Get rid of it.
Now, this font, this
is some Times New Roman Helvetica.
Come on, brother. The Sans Serif fonts,
we can make this look nicer.
Black and white.
It looks like a screenshot from Microsoft
Word. Come on.
Okay, I want to know why these four
are the ones up here.
Now,
if these are your highest converting
videos, cool.
But in case you didn't know,
we go to YouTube, we go to YouTube Studio,
we come
down to Settings, Customization, Home tab,
and you can
determine which videos you want to show
people.
And I think that maybe for your videos,
you could put some of your biggest
hitters,
or you could put some of your popular
videos.
I think this could be a little bit
different.
The reason it's live streams,
I just don't know.
Instead, if we go to Videos, Popular.
"Should you do Usain Bolt speed workout?"
Maybe even put that one there for a
little bit of an appeal to authority.
But I'll tell you what else would be a
very good thing to do.
Go to your Studio, go to your Analytics,
go to Advanced mode, the
place not many people go. And then
if we were to look at something like
subscribers,
we can then look across the lifetime what
video
is growing your channel the most,
and we could go, cool, this one here,
growing it the most. Maybe I put
that as the channel trailer.
Or maybe we want something with big watch
time.
Maybe it's watch time that's really going
to be the thing that grows the channel.
We could put that video there.
What's important to you?
Maybe something with a massive
click-through rate.
But remember,
this can be skewed because
if a video's bombed, the click-through
rate doesn't plummet because the algorithm
never took it wide.
Or we take the video with the biggest
amount of views, and we can put
that there.
It's up to you. You're progressive.
What benefits your business the best?
When I land on your page-
If your goal is to get-
... hit me with that
... faster, it's actually pretty hard.
You-
So yeah,
this for you could be curated a bit
better.
Let's have a look at your community wall.
Active. Love to see it.
Straight to landing page, which is cool.
Don't get me wrong.
Straight to landing page is okay,
but you're trying to give something.
If you send people just to your landing
page, it's like going, "Hey,
I think you're
really attractive and that.
Would you like to come home
and suck my penis?" People
are like, "No. Get the fuck away,
you creep." Whereas instead, you're like,
"Hey,
don't usually do this.
Think you're beautiful.
I'd love to take you for a drink." You'd
love to take me for a drink?
You'd like to do something for me?
Wonderful. Where do I sign up?
Next minute,
they could be sucking your penis.
And the reason I say that
is you don't want to seem too pushy.
You want to say,
"I have something of value
that I can give you that can change
your life." And that's where I think email
marketing, like a nice automation, could
come in. I'm going to show you.
Before you say, "What's that?" Show, don't
tell. And remember,
if you want me to do this to your social
media critique,
there's a link in the description.
You're getting to that. Get it in there.
Get it in there. This bullshit here,
"Prove to us that you're not a robot."
You're a robot, fam.
The fucking machines trying to get...
Another one. Fucking hell.
How dodgy do I fucking look like? Okay.
AWeber. You go to your Automations.
This is how I do it.
So I've got these everywhere. Send email,
wait 24 hours, send email,
wait 24 hours, send email, wait 24 hours,
send email.
If you want a taste of that,
in the description as well,
there's going to be 30
ways in 30 days that can benefit your
business.
Now,
even if you're not interested in my
business advice, just fucking sign up to
it because you're going to see how I close
people.
Now, the thing is, these views, 5,000,
2,000, 4,000, 4,0000, I don't think is
bad at all.
In this video,
I'm going to show you how to train for
pure sprint speed.
I'm going to lay out the-
Okay. I'm sure these videos are great.
The one thing I want to see here
is something that sits between you,
your content, and your product.
And it's going to be a free resource.
I think it's Faster in 40. Just made
that up. Faster in 40, Justin.
40 ways, 40 days, make me faster.
And every day you're going to turn up,
you're going to come into my email inbox,
and I'm going to go, "Fuck me a cunt.
This is fucking helpful.
Didn't know about this."
If your goal is to get-
"That's well interesting."
And then by day 32, I'm going to go,
"Do you know what?
There's not one person in the world other
than Justin who I'm going to
give my business to to make me faster."
There is so much going right with this,
but
I feel like a bigger email list could be
better. Bigger, better.
Bigger, better.
Because let's say you release,
I'm speculating here, one of
them shoots that you run
that causes drag or whatever.
You got an email list of 35,000 people.
"Hey, guys. Created this.
Do you want it?" Chuck it out there.
1,500 orders. Cash money.
Love to see this niche. There
are so many athletes like myself
when I was younger
that just never did any work to get
faster.
I want to see you branching out to other
niches. Let me show you.
Every single rugby player in the world
wants to be Henry Pollock.
Once again,
just those extra few meters. Pollock
He got sucked in and he is gone.
That should be illegal to be that fast
and play in the back row.
Should be illegal.
The guy's 20. He's 20. He's carving up.
And I know what you're thinking.
You're probably thinking, "Hey, man,
I'm from America.
What about Carlin Isles, brother?
What about Carlin Isles?
Let's get that rugby sprint." Who's Carlin
Isles? What? Let me show you.
Caught it nicely by
Vunipola. Hacked down the back.
Elvira comes into the fray
and keeps it alive.
Lovely one-two, and now Carlin Isles-
Pretty sure he's the fastest man in world
rugby
... in the red headband.
Because guess what? There
are a lot of sprinters
that want to get faster.
And you know what?
Adding a second here
and there to someone's 100 meter,
cool. But if you make a rugby player 20,
30% faster, my days,
that's more line breaks,
that's more getting selected in the first
team, that's
more opportunities,
that's better contracts.
That's getting picked up
and playing for your country. Sorry,
I get excited.
If I was quick playing rugby,
I still would've been pretty average,
but I could've
been better average.
Hope you enjoyed the video.
Check out the links in the description,
and I'll see you next time.